curvefever.com 2019-09-02

# Privacy and Cookie Notice | Curve Fever Forum - 2011

We are Hidden Monster Games B.V. We are based at Spuistraat 104 D, 1012 VA Amsterdam, The Netherlands. You can contact us at supporthiddenmonster.games if you have questions about data protection, or if you have any requests for resolving issues with your personal data.

We publish Curve Fever. Curve Fever is a game that can be played in your browser. We also operate related sites to our game, such as the forums or our company site. This privacy policy applies to our game and related sites. They are:

  * curvefever.com
  * curvefever.io
  * curvefever.pro
  * achtungdiekurve.net
  * forum.curvefever.com
  * forum.curvefever.pro
  * hiddenmonster.games

In this privacy notice we describe:

  * The ways we collect personal data about you when you play Curve Fever or subscribe to  our newsletter, when you visit our website, and why we do so,
  * How we use your personal data, and
  * The choices you have about your personal data.

_As a controller, we are committed to a lawful, fair and transparent processing of personal data, adhering to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)._

## 1\. The data we process

When you play our game, make an account or a purchase of in-game currency, post or respond to messages on our forum, or interact with us, we process the following information:

  * Username and email address.
  * The contents of forum posts, private messages and chat messages
  * Account information (including a country if you provided one) and payment information.
  * Login and navigational data.
  * Bug reports, suggestions for improvements
  * Customer support messages

In addition, when you visit our website or play our game, we and our analytics, payment and advertizing providers collect and process data such as your IP address and mobile device identifiers (such as your device ID, advertising ID, MAC address, IMEI), data about your device, such as device name and operating system, browser type and language, and data about how you use the game and website. For this purpose our partners are Google Analytics and DeltaDNA.

## 2\. What do we use the data for, and on what legal basis

We use username and email address to provide you with an account (a contract with you) or when you subscribe to our newsletter (on the basis of your consent).

We use the content of forum posts, private messages and chat messages to provide you with the service (a contract with you) and to monitor content for compliance with our community rules (the legitimate interest of us and other players to have a safe environment to play our games in).

We use account information and payment information to provide you with the game, and the possibility to buy in-game currency (a contract with you).

We use login and navigational data to help with navigating around web pages or accessing secure areas of the website (a contract with you). Without these cookies, the website cannot function properly.

We use bug reports and suggestions for improvements for exactly those purposes: bug report and to communicate about possible improvement to our websites and games (our legitimate interest in being able to hear about issues with our service and to troubleshoot).

We use customers support message to provide support to you (a contract with you).

We use analytics and advertising data, and social plug-ins to be able to allow third-parties to show you ads on our websites so that we can generate revenue (our legitimate interest). 

## 3\. Who we share data with

We do not actively share data with any third-parties, other than processors acting on our behalf.

We have also engaged third-parties for analytics and advertising, and social plug-ins. How they capture and use data is described under Cookies and other technologies.

Finally, as we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, bankruptcy, dissolution or similar event, your information may be part of the transferred assets.

## 4\. How long and where do we store data

If you made an account, we store data until you delete your account. We store other non-account related personal data that we collect for up to a year, and only aggregate data after that time. Aggregation data means that we can no longer look at data for individual players.

When a third-party service provider is a controller, they may keep data as well, either for a shorter or longer period.

We store newsletter subscriber information until such subscriber indicates they no longer want to receive the newsletter.

We store analytics and advertising data (insofar we have access) for up to 5 years to be able to analyze seasonal and mid-term trends.

## 5\. How do we protect data

Taking into account the nature, scope, context and purpose of the processing, we have taken the following technical and organizational measures:

  * Access to our database and user accounts with third-party service providers is protected with access control.
  * Access to the database is limited, not all staff in our organization have full access.

We do not actively monitor the security of our database and need to rely on our processors to notify us of any data breaches.

## 6\. Transfer of your personal data

You should also know that your personal data may be transferred from your home country to third parties. If you are an EU resident, this could imply that we also transfer data to countries that do not offer an adequate level of protection for your personal data. When we transfer this data, we will do so only when we have put in place appropriate safeguards to protect your personal data. Please contact us to get a copy of the safeguards that we have put in place.

## 7\. Children

Our Services are for users age 13 and over and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 and believe he or she has disclosed personal information to us please contact us at supporthiddenmonster.games.

For residents of the EEA, where processing of personal information is based on consent, we will not knowingly engage in that processing for users under the age of consent established by applicable data protection law, either under 13 or under 16, depending on where you live.

## 8\. Your rights

If you reside in the European Union, you have the right to request access to your personal data that we process. You also have the right to rectify incorrect personal data or erase it in certain circumstances, to restrict or object to the processing of your personal data and to receive your data so that you can use it elsewhere (data portability).

Where we process data based on your consent, you also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time but we would like to point out that this does not affect the lawfulness of the processing before the date that you withdrew your consent.

If you would like to exercise any of the above right, you can do so by sending us a mail to privacyhiddenmonster.games . We will then start the process and provide you a link to access the personal data that Curve Fever has on you within 30 days. For your protection, we may take steps to verify identity before responding to your request.

The rights and options described above are subject to limitations and exceptions under applicable law. In addition to those rights, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority. However, we encourage you to contact us first, and we will do our very best to resolve your concern.

You can also unsubscribe from our newsletter by clicking the “unsubscribe” link that each newsletter email has.

## 9\. Cookies and other technologies

Like most online services, we and our partners use cookies and similar technologies to provide and personalize our website, analyze use, target advertisements and prevent fraud. You can disable cookies in your browser settings, but some parts of the website may then not function properly. We have identified the following cookies placed on our website:

**Name**

| 

**How Long**

| 

**Placed By**

| 

**Reason**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
accessToken

| 

100 years

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Your session authentication token to login to our game  
  
gameAddress

| 

100 years

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Address of the game server you were connect to, used for rejoining games.  
  
gameToken

| 

100 years

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Access token to connect to latest game server, used for rejoining games.  
  
roomID

| 

100 years

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

The ID of the room you were connected to, used for rejoining games.  
  
cookieconsent_status

| 

1 year

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Whether or not you accepted the cookie consent message.  
  
announcements-seen

| 

Forever

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

List of announcements you have seen so you don’t see them anymore.  
  
logLevel

| 

Forever

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Type of messages logged in the console.  
  
curve-fever_cookiecontrol

| 

90 days

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

Store cookie preferences.  
  
sessionID

| 

Session

| 

DeltaDNA Ltd.

| 

Session ID for analytic tracking. With DeltaDNA (<https://deltadna.com/privacy/>)  
  
has_js

| 

Session

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

When a browser renders a page generated by Drupal (our forum software), a piece of JavaScript is executed which adds a cookie (has_js=1). This allows Drupal to generate different markup depending on whether the user agent is capable of executing JavaScript or not.  
  
_t

_forum_session

rack.session

| 

60 days

60 days

60 days

| 

Hidden Monster Games BV

| 

We use discourse forum software. The forum software ads cookies to track your session and keep you logged in after closing the browser  
  
_gat

_ga  
_gid

| 

1 minute

2 years

24 hours

| 

Google Inc.

| 

We use Google Analytics and Doubeclick. This is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. to count visitors to our websites and analyse their usage of the site to help us determine the value of our content to our users. [www.google.com/policies/privacy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy).  
  
__gads

OGPC

NID

SSID

SAPSID

APISID

1P_JAR

HSID

SIDCC

SID

DSID

IDE

test_cookie

| 

2 days

60 days

6 months

2 years

2 years

2 years

2 years

2 years

2 years

2 years

1 hour

25 days

Session

| 

Google Inc.

| 

We use Google to serve you ads. Google uses cookies to make advertising more engaging to users and more valuable to publishers and advertisers. Some common applications of cookies are to select advertising based on what’s relevant to a user; to improve reporting on campaign performance; and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen. <https://policies.google.com/technologies/types>  
  
__ur_q

__ur_

 __bpn_uid

__ur_dc

__ur_dc

_ga

| 

1 year

1 year

1 year

1 year

1 year

1 year

| 

UserReport

| 

We use UserReport on our websites to gather feedback from users. UserReport causes some cookies to be created by UserReport. These cookies are used to gather information about surveys and feedback forms. Refer to UserReport's cookie policy for further details. <https://www.userreport.com/cookie-policy/>  
  
c_user

presence

datr

xs

sb

spin

pl

act

lu

| 

90 days

session

2 years

session

session

session

session

session

2 years

| 

Facebook

| 

We use the Facebook Like button to integrate our website with our page on Facebook.com - a common feature of websites these days. In doing so this causes some cookies to be created by Facebook that detect the number of "likes" and whether you are logged into Facebook or not. You should refer to Facebook's cookie policy here. At the last count Facebook use 12 cookies which all expire at the end of the browser session with the exception of datr (2 years), fr (2 months) and lu (2 years). <http://www.pickmaster.co.uk/cookie-policy>  
  
__cfduid

| 

1 year

| 

Cloudflare

| 

We use cloudflare to speed up loading times and protect our sites from attacks. Cookie assoiated with sites using CloudFlare, used to speed up page load times. According to CloudFlare it is used to override any security restrictions based on the IP address the visitor is coming from. It does not contain any user identification information. <https://www.cloudflare.com/cookie-policy/>     
  
## 10\. Version information

This policy was last updated on 24 July 2018

It can be viewed on: <http://forum.curvefever.com/content/privacy-and-cookie-notice>
